=The Origin of Eternity=
= أصل الخلود =
=Episode 20=
= الحلقة 20 =
♪Migrating swan geese fly before my eager eyes♪
♪ إوز البجعة المهاجرة تطير أمام عيني المتلهفة ♪
♪But never return after spring♪
♪ لكن لا تعود بعد الربيع
♪Under the lonely waxing crescent, with a worried and pale face♪
تحت الهلال المنعزل ، ووجهه شاحب وقلق
♪I have no one to drink with♪
♪ ليس لدي من أشرب معه ♪
♪My yearnings are scattered when the sun goes down♪
تشتت أشواقي عند غروب الشمس
♪Like snow flying all over the sky♪
♪ مثل الثلج المتطاير في جميع أنحاء السماء
♪Fearless, the falling flowers love the eastern river♪
♪ بلا خوف ، الزهور المتساقطة تحب النهر الشرقي
♪All for nothing, resembling someone we know♪
كل شيء مقابل لا شيء ، يشبه شخصًا نعرفه
♪I fear the past perishes in a flash♪
♪ أخشى أن يموت الماضي في ومضة ♪
♪And more, I fear travelling the world alone♪
♪ وأكثر من ذلك ، أخشى السفر حول العالم وحدي
♪Reminiscing the memories amidst tipsiness♪
♪ استحضار الذكريات وسط النشوة ♪
♪Missing out on the loved one while growing old♪
♪ فقدان من تحب أثناء تقدمك في العمر ♪
♪I fear the past perishes in a flash♪
♪ أخشى أن يموت الماضي في ومضة ♪
♪I even fear thinking of the sky meeting the sea♪
♪ حتى أنني أخشى التفكير في لقاء السماء بالبحر
♪Every visit to the mortal realm, meeting you brings more suffering♪
♪ في كل زيارة إلى عالم البشر ، يجلب لك مقابلتك المزيد من المعاناة
♪There's no love in the world that brings no tears♪
♪ لا يوجد حب في العالم لا يبكي
Your Majesty,
جلالة الملك ،
I've returned.
لقد عدت.
Have you prepared
هل أعددت
your wedding gown?
ثوب الزفاف الخاص بك؟
I've prepared it long ago.
لقد أعددته منذ فترة طويلة.
I was awaiting your return
كنت أنتظر عودتك
so that I could be your bride.
حتى أكون عروسك.
♪Fearless, the falling flowers love the eastern river♪
♪ بلا خوف ، الزهور المتساقطة تحب النهر الشرقي
♪All for nothing, resembling someone we know♪
كل شيء مقابل لا شيء ، يشبه شخصًا نعرفه
♪I fear the past perishes in a flash♪
♪ أخشى أن يموت الماضي في ومضة ♪
♪And more, I fear travelling the world alone♪
♪ وأكثر من ذلك ، أخشى السفر حول العالم وحدي
♪Reminiscing the memories amidst tipsiness♪
♪ استحضار الذكريات وسط النشوة ♪
You!
أنت!
I'm sorry.
أنا آسف.
You lied to me?
أنت كذبت علي؟
Your Majesty,
جلالة الملك ،
I swear
أقسم
that today's my last time lying to you.
أن آخر مرة أكذب عليك فيها اليوم.
From now on,
من الان فصاعدا،
in this life,
في هذه الحياة،
next life,
الحياة القادمة،
and the life after, I'll always be yours.
والحياة بعد ذلك ، سأكون لك دائمًا.
Next life
الحياة القادمة
and the life after?
والحياة بعد ذلك؟
I trusted you.
انا وثقت بك.
I hid nothing from you.
لم اخف عنك شيئا.
However, you weren't sincere with me at all!
ومع ذلك ، لم تكن صادقًا معي على الإطلاق!
The Ling Empire and Great Sheng have been rivals for generations.
كانت إمبراطورية Ling و Great Sheng منافسين لأجيال.
How could we not plot against each other?
كيف لا نتآمر ضد بعضنا البعض؟
You've deceived me too, haven't you?
لقد خدعتني أيضًا ، أليس كذلك؟
Yes.
نعم.
I did deceive you regarding the incident with the Third Prince.
لقد خدعتك فيما يتعلق بالحادثة مع الأمير الثالث.
However, what about
ومع ذلك ، ماذا عن
the moments we enjoyed together?
اللحظات التي استمتعنا بها معًا؟
Were they all fake?
هل كانت كلها مزيفة؟
I loved you from the start until the end!
أحببتك من البداية حتى النهاية!
Yes.
نعم.
My plan could only succeed
يمكن أن تنجح خطتي فقط
due to your love for me.
بسبب حبك لي.
You're truly something else.
أنت حقًا شيء آخر.
Weren't you afraid that I would slay you out of spite
ألم تكن خائفًا من أن أقتلك حقدًا
during the uprising of Lord Yong?
خلال انتفاضة اللورد يونغ؟
No pain, no gain.
لا ألم, لا ربح.
It was a risky move to begin with.
لقد كانت خطوة محفوفة بالمخاطر في البداية.
How could I win your trust
كيف يمكنني كسب ثقتك
and make you give me the tiger tally
وتجعلك تعطيني حصيلة النمر
if I didn't put myself in a risky situation as such?
إذا لم أضع نفسي في موقف محفوف بالمخاطر على هذا النحو؟
I'm not as ruthless as you.
أنا لست قاسياً مثلك.
I've lost.
لقد فقدت.
No.
لا.
Qinghuan, you didn't lose.
Qinghuan ، أنت لم تخسر.
I love you.
أحبك.
After all that I've been through,
بعد كل ما مررت به ،
you led my army against me
لقد قادت جيشي ضدي
and put your sword against my neck.
واجعل سيفك على عنقي.
Now, you're saying that you love me?
الآن ، أنت تقول أنك تحبني؟
That's not it.
هذا ليس هو.
Qinghuan,
تشينغوان ،
you and I are members of the imperial family.
أنت وأنا أعضاء في العائلة الإمبراطورية.
We understand the responsibility we need to bear.
نحن نتفهم المسؤولية التي يجب أن نتحملها.
Yes.
نعم.
At most, I was faking it.
على الأكثر ، كنت أقوم بتزييفها.
But after that, I truly fell for you.
لكن بعد ذلك ، وقعت في حبك حقًا.
Maybe it was because you let me kiss you.
ربما كان ذلك لأنك تركتني أقبلك.
Maybe it was because you fended off the assassins for me.
ربما كان ذلك لأنك صدت القتلة من أجلي.
Maybe it was because
ربما كان ذلك بسبب
what we did on the bed.
ما فعلناه على السرير.
I once thought
اعتقدت ذات مرة
that I, Bai Ze, was born for the sake of the Ling Empire
أنني ، باي زي ، ولدت من أجل إمبراطورية لينج
and its people.
وناسها.
But when I met you,
لكن عندما التقيت بك ،
I realized
أدركت
that I wanted to be selfish for once.
أردت أن أكون أنانيًا لمرة واحدة.
I no longer wanted to live for their sake.
لم أعد أرغب في العيش من أجلهم.
I wish to live for myself.
أتمنى أن أعيش لنفسي.
I wish to be your husband.
أتمنى أن أكون زوجك.
I wish to grow old together with you,
أتمنى أن أتقدم في العمر معك ،
until death do us part.
حتى يفرقنا الموت.
It has already come to this.
لقد حان بالفعل لهذا.
Why are you still pretending?
لماذا مازلت تتظاهر؟
Qinghuan, I'm serious.
Qinghuan ، أنا جاد.
I truly love you!
أحبك بصدق!
As long as you surrender,
ما دمت تستسلم ،
I'll elect you as the Empress of Great Ling.
سأنتخبك لتكون إمبراطورة غريت لينغ.
If we truly love each other,
إذا كنا نحب بعضنا البعض حقًا ،
what's the difference between me making you my empress
ما الفرق بين أن أجعلك إمبراطورة لي
and you making me your monarch?
وأنت تجعلني ملكك؟
You're asking me what's the difference?
أنت تسألني ما هو الفرق؟
This is the difference.
هذا هو الاختلاف.
Qinghuan,
تشينغوان ،
it's too late.
فات الأوان.
It's pointless for you to kill me.
من العبث أن تقتلني.
Your Majesty!
جلالة الملك!
The prisoner army has already surrounded the capital of Sheng!
جيش الأسرى قد حاصر بالفعل عاصمة شنغ!
The imperial army
الجيش الإمبراطوري
has been annihilated!
قد أبيد!
Qinghuan,
تشينغوان ،
just stop.
توقف.
Just let me love you, okay?
فقط دعني أحبك ، حسنًا؟
If I kill you right now,
إذا قتلتك الآن ،
the prisoner army will fall apart
جيش الأسرى سوف ينهار
as they have no leader.
لأنه ليس لديهم زعيم.
Even if you kill me,
حتى لو قتلتني
Third Prince will avenge me.
الأمير الثالث سوف ينتقم لي.
By then, the people will be the only ones who suffer.
بحلول ذلك الوقت ، سيكون الناس هم الوحيدون الذين يعانون.
So, even the Third Prince was one of your pawns?
لذا ، حتى الأمير الثالث كان أحد بيادقك؟
Ever since you stepped into the state of Great Sheng,
منذ أن دخلت دولة شينغ العظيم ،
all of your moves
كل تحركاتك
were planned out in advance!
تم التخطيط لها مسبقا!
Qinghuan, that's not true.
Qinghuan ، هذا ليس صحيحًا.
I truly love you! Please believe me!
أحبك بصدق!  أرجوك صدقني!
I'll treat you well
سوف أعاملك بشكل جيد
as long as you surrender
ما دمت تستسلم
the throne to me,
العرش لي
okay?
تمام؟
Qinghuan, please trust me.
Qinghuan ، الرجاء ثق بي.
Qinghuan,
تشينغوان ،
trust me one last time.
ثق بي للمرة الأخيرة.
I don't need you to treat me well.
لا أريدك أن تعاملني جيدًا.
Just treat my people well.
فقط عامل شعبي بشكل جيد.
All right.
حسنًا.
I promise you.
أعدك.
I'll treat the subjects and people of
سوف أعالج مواضيع وأشخاص
Great Sheng well if you become my empress.
عظيم شنغ جيد إذا أصبحت إمبراطوريتي.
I swear.
أقسم.
Fine.
بخير.
Thank you,
شكرًا لك،
Your Majesty.
جلالة الملك.
Qinghuan!
تشينغوان!
♪Wandered off from the crowd♪
تاهت عن الحشد ♪
♪As more wonderful things await♪
♪ كما تنتظر المزيد من الأشياء الرائعة
♪A sunset from the past resurfaced♪
انعكاس غروب الشمس من الماضي
♪Thousands of sailboats drifted in the sea of clouds♪
جرفت آلاف المراكب الشراعية في بحر السحب
♪And docked at different piers♪
♪ ورست على أرصفة مختلفة ♪
♪Only the catkin willow and my graying hair remained♪
فقط صفصاف القطة وشعري الشيب بقي
♪Let's take on♪
♪ لنأخذ
♪Another year♪
♪ سنة أخرى ♪
♪I traveled alone toward daytime as I waved aside the night♪
سافرت لوحدي في النهار بينما كنت ألوح جانباً في الليل
♪The tapping rain♪
مطر التنصت ♪
♪Awakened the sorrow♪
أيقظ الحزن
♪I'm crying out in loneliness amid pandemonium♪
♪ أنا أبكي في عزلة وسط الهرج والمرج
♪I endured countless ordeals from worldly entanglement♪
لقد تحملت محن لا حصر لها من التشابك الدنيوي ♪
♪Knowing how difficult things are for the first time♪
معرفة مدى صعوبة الأمور لأول مرة ♪
♪After you overcome the vicissitudes of life♪
بعد أن تتغلب على تقلبات الحياة
♪Only then do you understand the fickleness of the world♪
"عندها فقط تفهم تقلب العالم"
♪I wanted to enjoy the years but it turned into a disaster overnight♪
♪ أردت الاستمتاع بالسنوات لكنها تحولت إلى كارثة بين عشية وضحاها
♪Knowing that I can't turn back time♪
♪ مع العلم أنني لا أستطيع العودة بالزمن ♪
♪You would not be intoxicated by sorrow♪
لن تسكر بالحزن
♪Until you were embroiled in love♪
حتى تتورط في الحب ♪
♪I wanted to enjoy the years but it turned into a disaster overnight♪
♪ أردت الاستمتاع بالسنوات لكنها تحولت إلى كارثة بين عشية وضحاها
♪Knowing that I can't turn back time♪
♪ مع العلم أنني لا أستطيع العودة بالزمن ♪
♪You would not be intoxicated by sorrow♪
لن تسكر بالحزن
♪Until you were embroiled in love♪
حتى تتورط في الحب ♪